Guide to the Emil A. Kohm accounts, 1908-1945.
Kohm, Emil A. accounts, 1908-1945.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Emil A. Kohm accounts, 1908-1945.
2065
Emil A. Kohm, 1870-1942.
.7 cubic ft.
Accounts, cashbooks, wage records, correspondence, and other records.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Customers' accounts, cashbooks, and wage records (6 vols.); also, letters and accounts concerning the tailoring business, the settlement of the Kohm estate, and other matters.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Emil A. Kohm was born in Germany and worked as a tailor in Ithaca, New York.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Customers' accounts, cashbooks, and wage records (6 vols.); also, letters and accounts concerning the tailoring business, the settlement of the Kohm estate, and other matters.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Kohm, Emil A., 1870-1942.
Subjects:
Decedents' estates--New York (State)--Ithaca.; Tailoring.; Tailors.
Places:
Ithaca (N.Y.)--Commerce.
Form and Genre Terms:
Account books.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Bound volumes
  - Customers' accounts, 1908, 1911-1929, 1938. Include (pp. 510-512) personal expense accounts, 1921-1929, of G.L. Brunne, who was in partnership with Kohm in the 1920s. Poor condition - spine damaged. 772 pp. (Box 2)
  - Daily cash receipts, 1921-1929. 445 pp. (Box 1)
  - Customers' accounts (large red ledger), 1929-1943. Indexed. 294 pp. used. (Box 3)
  - Customers' address book (slim red ledger). Possibly some personal or family addresses - German ones. 1937 [?]. (Box 3)
  - Record of weekly wages paid, 1937-Jan. 1, 1940. Information on names and social security numbers of employees also included. (Box 2)
  - Weekly cash book, 1941-1945. Kohm Estate [?]. (Box 2)
- Loose accounts, letters, and rough notes concerning the tailor's business and the settlement of the Kohm estate, 1917-1945
  - Promissory note made in favor of Kohm & Brunne - signature A.R. Cota (?) dated June 18, 1917 at the Ithaca Trust Co. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Promissory note made in favor of Kohm & Brunne - signature C.E. Finney dated Oct. 4, 1923 at Citizens Trust Co. of Summit, N.J. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 5 sheets of figures, July 1, 1923-July 1, 1929. These seem to be itemized lists of bills paid by the business for both Kohm and Brunne (includes cash drawn by each). (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Common Stock Certificate #99 for 75 shares of capital stock of the Terrien Oil Co. dated Aug. 31, 1927 issued to Kohm and Brunne. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Bill to Bruce Simmons from E.A. Kohm dated Oct. 5, 1942. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Sample of dunning letter (for outstanding accounts in Kohm's business) dated Aug. 10, 1942 - handwritten note at bottom asks for approval of letter form. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Letter to Raymond Kohm from James W. Andrews dated Aug. 29, 1944 re: accounting for settlement of judgment against Alva S. Ainsworth. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Financial statement - Emil A. Kohm estate, June 15, 1942-July 24, 1944. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Lists of names and amounts (otherwise unidentified), Jan. 12, 1945-Nov. 16, ? (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Items found in bound volume of The Widow and removed
  - Carbon typescript directive from J.H. Dawson, U.S. Army, relieving Joseph H. Kohm of his full-time duty in the Army, May 8, 1919. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Telegram from Joseph Kohm to Emil Kohm re: his discharge, May 10, 1919. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Two snapshots of young girls: one girl alone; two girls together. (Box 3, Folder 2)